# RARES COSTIN MUNTEANU



+40763277778 | raresmunteanu29@yahoo.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with almost 5 years of experience in Cyber Security domain with implications mainly in vulnerability processing components. Over 4 years since working as a backend engineer, being passionate about api design and architecture.

I respond to challenges and I am open to always learn new things and improve projects i work with.

I am characterized by perseverance and the power of concentration. I am also a sociable person, who likes to interact with teammates both professionally and socially.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Python QA developer

HCL Technologies | Iași, Romania | July 2023 - Current

- Worked on maintaining and developing new automated tests for the HP Smart application
- · the used stack was: pytest, appium, selenium, Jenkins
- Resolved a large quantity of bad written or non-functional tests
- · Written new tests to automate manual test cases

#### **Senior Python Developer**

Lionstep | September 2022 - July 2023

- Implicated into the process of re-architecture and rewriting of the entire product in Python with fast API(mainly written in ruby rails)
- Created a new feature for the product to find similarities between jobs(machine learning knowledge involved). This feature was used by the entire company,

## **CORE QUALIFICATIONS**

- Python
- Git
- Web Crawling
- MongoDB
- Flask
- SQL
- AI
- Neural Networks
- Computer Networking
- Cyber Security
- REST
- Machine Learning
- Web Development
- FastAPI
- Pytest, Selenium, Appium
- Jenkins/Github Actions
- Data structures

# **EDUCATION**

lasi

M.Sc.: Computer Science,
Computational Optimization
July 2022

enhancing the recruiter's capability by 70 %,

- CI/CD flows for automatic testing and deployment to Google Cloud
- · Written tests for API integration with pytest
- Working with both types of databases(NoSQL Datastore and SQL postgres)
- Had the chance to work also with elastic search(templates, indexes, etc)

#### **Software Engineer**

Bitdefender | Iasi | May 2018 - August 2022

- Designed and developed API that is used to correlate vulnerabilities with products installed on endpoints
- This component plays a key role and represents over 60 % of Vulnerabilities
   Detection process
- Designed and developed tool that will be used to identify critical resources in a company
- This component will be a big part in prioritizing security measures taken on company endpoints
- This project will use and correlate information from millions of endpoints
- This project is based on my Computer Science Degree
- Designed and developed a component that creates an internet surfing profiling and retrieves a risk score for each user
- The amount of data that is processed is of the order of billions entries each week
- This component will have a great impact on endpoints and companies at vulnerability assessment level
- Designed and developed a component that process multiple feeds from
- NVD(National Vulnerability Database) to construct correlations between cpes and
- There are 3 feeds, that contains millions of entries that need to be processed
- This database is the core of vulnerability detection process and represents 100% of the vulnerabilities information owned
- Designed, developed and maintained over 5 crawlers used to extract and manipulate different types of data
- Research in vulnerability field
- From this research, over 200 risk indicators were created that played a big role in

GPA: 9.50

lasi

B.Sc: Computer Science
July 2020

Finished: Computer Science

GPA: 9.25

vulnerability detection components

- Most of the components presented above implies working with big flow of data, mainly non relational databases (MongoDB) and modules used for API design (Flask)
- Maintaining different projects that implied working with virtual machines, different rdp connections, etc
- This projects are part of Vulnerability Assessment also.

# **Teaching Assistant**

Faculty of Computer Science Iasi | Iasi | October 2020 - October 2022

- Responsible for teaching Python Programming subject laboratory classes to 3rd year students
- That implies teaching, resolving problems with students and answer to a variety of questions
- This experience not only improved my speech and the ability to speak in front of other peoples, specially new ones, but also made me realize how many things i need to learn and improve
- The teaching act means a a perpetual work that is the base for mastering a domain.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Romanian: First Language

3 3			
German:	A1	English:	C1
Beginner		Advanced	